(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
僕たちは配信アプリ ホロキャスで活動する配信者
We're streamers who are active on a streaming app called HoloCast.
突然画面に吸い込まれて アプリとつながる謎の世界 ホロキャス界に来ちゃった
Suddenly sucked into the screen, we ended up in the mysterious HoloCast world connected to the app.
そこでは 現実で苦しむ人の魂が怪物化してしまう現象 夢落ちが起こっていた
There, a phenomenon called 'Dreamfall' was turning the souls of suffering people into monsters.
怪物コラプサーを倒して みんなの魂を取り戻さないと
We have to defeat the monster Corruptors and get everyone's souls back!
そうして 魔法少女に変身して 戦うことになった
And so, we transformed into magical girls and fought.
みんなの心を助けて 夢を応援する
We'll save everyone's hearts and support their dreams.
それが 魔法少女ホロウィッチ！
That's who we are: Magical Girl Holowitches!
今日はスペシャルハロウィンステージ！
Today is the Special Halloween Stage!
ホロキャスの人気配信者が多数出演
Many popular HoloCast streamers will be performing.
さらに 今をときめく超人気歌手の叶夢さんも参加 超超豪華イベント
Even the super-popular singer Kaname is joining this super-extravagant event!
で その超豪華イベントのオープニングアクトをウチら6人が担当することになって
And the six of us were chosen to be the opening act for that super-event.
せっかくだし みんなでホロウィッチの衣装を着て ドカンと派手に盛り上げちゃおうかなって
I thought we'd all wear our Holowitches costumes and really liven things up!
でもいいのかな？ 魔法とか 妖精とか 一応内緒なんだけど
But is it okay? Magic and fairies and all... it's supposed to be a secret.
今日はハロウィンだから 仮装ってことにすれば なんとかなるなる！
Since it's Halloween, if we just call them costumes, it'll be fine!
そうそう ってそろそろ準備したほうがよくない？
Exactly. Anyway, shouldn't we start getting ready?
そうだね！ じゃ 気合入れていきますか！
You're right! Let's get fired up!
トリック・オア
Trick or...
トリート！
Treat!
魔法少女ホロウィッチ！THE STAGE TRICK or MAGIC!
Magical Girl HoloWitch! THE STAGE TRICK or MAGIC!
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
みんな、盛り上がってるー？
Is everyone fired up?
ホロウィッチのオープニングアクト、どうだったー？
How was the HoloWitch opening act?
ここからもっともっと盛り上げていくから、
We're going to keep firing things up even more from here,
みんなで一緒に楽しもうねー！
so let's all have fun together!
今日は我々ホロキャスの配信者だけじゃなく、
Today, it's not just us HoloCast streamers,
あの超人気歌手、カノンさんがゲストで来てくださってまーす！
the super popular singer, Kanon-san, is here as a special guest!
カノンさん、どうぞー！
Kanon-san, please come out!
トリック・オア・トリート。
Trick or Treat.
みんな、今日は最後まで
Everyone, please stay with us
よろしく。
until the very end.
いやまさかね、あのカノンさんと同じステージに立てるとは。
I can't believe it. Getting to stand on the same stage as Kanon-san.
いや本当、憧れですよ。
Yeah, really, she's an idol to us.
カノンさんの歌を聴くと、すっごくパワーもらえるのら！
When I hear Kanon-san's songs, I get so much energy!
そうそう、こんなにいただいちゃっていいんですかーってくらいね。
Yeah, exactly. To the point where I feel like I'm receiving too much.
うーん、めっちゃ元気出ますよねー。
Mm, it really lifts your spirits, doesn't it?
ありがとう。なんでもないから。
Thank you. It's nothing.
次の曲は、みんなも一緒に歌ってほしいのらー！
For the next song, I want everyone to sing along!
君たち、遠慮しないで声出してね、声！
You guys, don't hold back and let me hear your voices!
君の声を聴かせて
Let me hear your voice
さあ冒険してみない？
Come on, won't you go on an adventure?
楽しいこと始めよう
Let's start something fun
遊びたい 絶対
I want to play, definitely!
とぅ たいっ! たいっ! たいっ!
To tai! tai! tai!
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and joy and happy people
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and joy and happy people
弱虫なんじゃない
I'm not a coward
自信ありげにピースサイン
A confident peace sign
君の瞳にキスして
I'll kiss your eyes
笑いたい 絶対
I want to laugh, definitely!
とぅ たいっ! たいっ! たいっ!
To tai! tai! tai!
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and joy and happy people
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYな SAY YAY!
Joy and joy and joy and happy, say yay!
君の心はそっと DO-DO
Your heart is softly Do-Do
僕の心もそっと IS-SO
My heart is also softly Is-so
はじけてるんじゃない？
Aren't they bursting?
IT'S JOYFUL POPなベイベー
It's Joyful, pop baby
POPなベイベー
Pop baby
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and joy and happy people
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and joy and happy people
ドキドキしちゃうの なんでだろう
Why does my heart race?
ズキズキしちゃうの なんでだろう
Why is it throbbing?
この夢に捕まるのは
Getting caught in this dream...
どんな運命なんだろう
...what kind of fate is it?
救われたい
I want to be saved
JOYFUL だけで終わっちゃう
Ending with just Joyful
EVERYBODY いま終わっちゃう
Everybody, it's ending now
いついつまでもこの時を
This moment forever and ever
最終回はきっと 修正なしで
The final episode will surely be unedited
とぅ たいっ! たいっ! たいっ!
To tai! tai! tai!
テンポ テンポ HAPPYなピーポー
Tempo tempo, happy people
たいっ! たいっ! たいっ! たいっ! たいっ!
Tai! tai! tai! tai! tai!
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and joy and happy people
I wanna JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
I wanna joy and joy and joy and pop baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYな SAY YAY!
Joy and joy and joy and happy, say yay!
君の心はそっと DO-DO
Your heart is softly Do-Do
僕の心もそっと IS-SO
My heart is also softly Is-so
はじけてるんじゃない？
Aren't they bursting?
IT'S JOYFUL POPなベイベー
It's Joyful, pop baby
JOY!
JOY!!
そ、みんな、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！
So, everyone, thank you for singing along with me!
いや、よかったね！会場がね、一体になったって感じでね。うん。
Wow, that was great! It felt like the venue really became one. Yeah.
よかったよかった！テンション上がるわ、これ！
Good, good! This really pumps me up!
さ、さあ次は、いよいよカノンさんに歌っていただきます！
Now, next, we'll finally have Kanon-san sing!
君、大丈夫？
Are you okay?
あ、何？！何なの？！
Ah, what?! What is it?!
取れないんだけど！
I can't get it off!
何これ？！
What is this?!
ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ！何なに？！どういうこと？！
Wait, wait, wait, wait! What, what?! What's going on?!
コラプサーだ！
It's a Corrupser!
ですよね、どう考えてもね！
Right, no matter how you look at it!
コラプサー、やっぱり。
Corrupser... as I thought.
外してー！
Take it off!
痛い痛い痛い！
Ow, ow, ow!
悪！
Evil!
怖い怖い怖い！
Scary, scary, scary!
えっーと、こういう時は……
Uh, at times like this...
ト、トリックオアトリート！
T-trick or treat!
何もかも違うだろう。
Everything about that is wrong.
フブキング、前後逆になってるよ！
Fubuki-ng, it's front-to-back!
みこち！出てる出てる！楽しいの素が出てる！
Mikochi! It's coming out! The essence of fun is coming out!
よいしょー！
Heave-ho!
だが、コラプサーが出てくるってことは……夢落ちしてる人がいるんだ、多分。
But, the fact that Corrupsers are appearing means... someone is falling into a dream state, probably.
ミオ先輩！
Mio-senpai!
ミオちゃん！
Mio-chan!
ごめん、うち……うち本当は、ハロウィンのカボチャが怖くてダメなの！
Sorry, I... I'm actually... I just can't handle Halloween pumpkins!
ただいまー。
I'm home.
うち、パパがカボチャに食べられちゃったんだって思っちゃって……
I thought Dad had been eaten by a pumpkin...
ハッピーハロウィーン！
Happy Halloween!
それから……
And then...
どうしても……
No matter what...
ハロウィンのカボチャだけは、無理なの！
Only Halloween pumpkins are just impossible for me!
チェンジ！
Change!
ガーディア・アーム！
Guardian Arm!
ミカメロン・ロッタ！
Micameron Lotta!
キャンディ・パラシャリュ！
Candy Parasharu!
頑張りな！
Give it your all!
スノーフレーク・セイバー！
Snowflake Saber!
吹雪丸！
Fubuki-maru!
ここは任せて、ミオ。
Leave this to us, Mio.
みんな……
Everyone...
魔法、みんなに見せちゃうけど、いいよね？
We're showing our magic to everyone, but that's okay, right?
うん、そんなこと言ってらんないし。
Yeah, we can't be saying things like that now.
だよね。夢落ちした人を助ける。それが……
Exactly. Saving people who have fallen into a dream state. That's what...
魔法少女、ホロウィッチ！
Magical Girl holoWitches!
この手を差し伸べ、掴んで、握る！
Reach out this hand, grab it, and hold on!
天使のホロ、魔法少女かなた！
Angel's Holo, Magical Girl Kanata!
みんなの願いを咲かせる祈り！
A prayer to make everyone's wishes bloom!
みこのホロ、魔法少女みこ！
Miko's Holo, Magical Girl Miko!
甘い幸せ、おっそ分け！
A sweet happiness, shared with you!
姫のホロ、魔法少女ルーナ！
Princess's Holo, Magical Girl Luna!
煌めくお宝、ロックオン！
Sparkling treasure, locked on!
海賊のホロ、魔法少女マリン！
Pirate's Holo, Magical Girl Marine!
心躍らすトリックスター！
The heart-dancing trickster!
狐のホロ、魔法少女フブキ！
Fox's Holo, Magical Girl Fubuki!
氷雪重なる純白の愛。
Snow and ice overlapping, pure white love.
雪のホロ、魔法少女ラミィ！
Snow of Holo, Magical Girl Lamy!
ホロウィッチ！フルキャスト！
HoloWitch! Full Cast!
行くよ！
Here I go!
ホイ！ポイ！
Hoi! Poi!
ハイ！
Hai!
パンプキン、敵じゃないよ。
Pumpkin, I'm not an enemy.
バカバカだよ。
I'm just a dummy.
コン！
Kon!
やめな。
Stop it.
えい！
Ei!
ね、なんかこれまずくない？
Hey, isn't this bad?
どんどん強くなっている。
It's getting stronger and stronger.
みんなが奴らを倒すより、
Faster than everyone can defeat them,
不安と恐れが膨れ上がる方が早いみたい！
it seems anxiety and fear are swelling up faster!
うそ、そんな...
No way, that's...
うちのせい...
It's my fault...
うちがあんなもの怖いって思っちゃうせいで...
Because I thought those things were scary...
そんなこと...
That's not true...
わかってるの。
I know.
おかしいよね、あんなのが
It's weird, isn't it? That those things...
こんなどうしようもなく怖いなんて。
...are so helplessly scary.
だから今日も我慢して、
That's why I tried to endure it today,
頑張ろうって思ったのに。
and do my best.
でも...
But...
でもやっぱり...
But still...
おかしくなんてないよ。
It's not weird at all.
カノンさん？
Kanon-san?
誰にだって苦手なものがある。
Everyone has things they're not good at.
怖いもの。嫌いなもの。
Things they fear. Things they hate.
人に何でそんなものがって言われても、
Even if people ask why you're like that,
どうしようもない事ってやっぱりあるよ。
there are things you just can't help.
そうだよ。
That's right.
何が苦手とか、何が怖いとかは関係なくて。
It doesn't matter what you're bad at or afraid of.
大事なのは、今、みおちゃんが辛いって思ってるかどうかだから。
The important thing is whether Mio-chan is feeling pain right now.
遠慮しないで。
Don't hold back.
頼ってほしいのら。
I want you to rely on us-nanora.
だってうちら、
Because we...
お互い様じゃん？
...are all in this together, right?
誰かの辛さ、誰かの苦手は、
Someone's pain, someone's weakness,
他の誰かがカバーする。
someone else will cover it.
お互いそうやって...
That's how we...
やってきたから、
We've come this far...
今がある。
...so we're here now!
こんなに頑張れる。
I can work this hard.
ホロウィッチ。
HoloWitch.
コラプターは、夢落ちした人の恐れと不安から生まれ、
Corruptors are born from the fear and anxiety of dream-fallen people,
その心を深く沈ませる。
sinking their hearts deep.
夢落ちって、
Dream-falling?
どうしてそれを？
How do you know that?
でも、私は知っている。
But, I know.
君たちなら、
If it's you,
ホロウィッチなら。
if it's HoloWitch.
辛い、苦しい、悲しい、きつい。
Painful, suffering, sad, tough.
そんな自分一人の力じゃ抜け出せない暗闇の中にいても、
Even in darkness you can't escape alone,
夢、光を届けてくれる。
you deliver dreams and light.
任せて！
Leave it to us!
例え幻想を吐いても、まだ終わらせない。
Even if illusions are spat out, I won't let it end yet.
さあ、みんな。
Now, everyone.
ホロウィッチが戦ってくれる。
HoloWitch will fight for us.
では、私たちにできるのは。
Then, what we can do...
そう、私たちの声で、思いで、彼女たちを応援することだ。
...is to cheer them on with our voices and feelings.
いざ、
Now...
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
「仮装狂騒曲」
作詞：TOPHAMHAT-KYO / 作曲：FAKE TYPE.
"Fancy Dress Party"
Lyrics: TOPHAMHAT-KYO / Composition: FAKE TYPE.
あれよという間に飲み込まれ
Swallowed up in the blink of an eye,
橙色のタイダルウェーブ やっこ やっこ
an orange tidal wave, yakko yakko.
ハンドメイドからオーダーメイドまで仕掛ける大流行
A huge craze from handmade to custom-made.
ハイ！
Hi!
本物から偽物までまぜまぜで大集合
Mixing everything from real to fake, big gathering.
ハイ！
Hi!
そんでもって不穏な世界にお揃いの衣装で
And in this turbulent world, in matching outfits,
エケケなこれ見よがしの奴隷よ
giggling ostentatious slaves,
同士よ 集え
comrades, gather!
夢式補正にホップステップトレイン
Hop-step-train to dream-style correction.
エールか喝采か 超に踊れよ
Whether cheers or applause, dance to the extreme!
ワンパン
One-pan!
チップにしたりされたりが人間でしょう
Tipping or being tipped, that's what being human is.
毎夜毎夜 物足りない君共
Every night, every night, you who are unsatisfied,
チョキッ 視界 期待
Snip! Sight, expectation,
ベイビーベリーベリーエブリセンステイティブ
baby, very very every sensitive.
あれよの間に 制御不能
In a flash, it's out of control
Universally Iggy minus Iggy viral mini mini mani mo
おそろしあ おそろ Hello!
Scary, so scary, Hello!
上り下り回り 月に針が落ちる
Rising, falling, spinning, a needle falls on the moon
お雛口で笑う かぼちゃ達の歌
Laughing with small mouths, the pumpkins' song
それが合図 魔物たちが目覚め踊る
That's the signal, the monsters wake up and dance
こうなれば後は 思いのまま
Once it's like this, the rest is as you wish
ホロウ 骨抜きダンスサボター
Holo! Boneless dance saboteur
スケアクロウも 飛び跳ね回る
Scarecrows also jump around
ホロウ 月夜のターンテーブル
Holo! Moonlit turntable
クルクル愛おしい高まり we got the party night!
Lovely, lovely excitement, we got the party night!
Anyway, enjoy the party night!
不気味なプー クスクス じゃらける空気じゃ無理
Eerie "pooh", giggles, impossible in a playful air
背徳に背徳はご法度で どさくさ紛れヘラヘラゲラヘーイ
Immorality on immorality is forbidden... (rap)
What's my 素敵なナイト 見つからなくても既にバラ色の
What's my lovely knight, even if not found, it's rose-colored...
不気味な着ぐるみ しまでから入る着るリグル
Eerie mascot costumes... (rap)
仮の姿も魂の本物ならば魅了 一致団結!
If the temporary form's soul is real, it's fascinating. United!
ガラパゴスに交わる異世界 大交流パーティー
Another world mixing in Galapagos, a great exchange party
振り切れる鼓動
A heartbeat that's breaking through
あどけないドラキュラ お酒を煽る
Innocent Dracula guzzling alcohol
潔白なデュラハン 頭を振る
Innocent Dullahan shaking its head
紳士的なミイラすら 服が解ける
Even a gentlemanly mummy, its clothes come loose
どうあれど愉快 全開のまま
No matter what, it's fun, fully open as it is
本性
True nature
露わに暴れよう
Let's rampage openly
その仮装も正装になる
Even that costume becomes formal wear
狂騒曲
Rhapsody
のターンテーブル
's turntable
アイアイ愛おしい高まり we got the party night!
Lovely, lovely excitement, we got the party night!
High five, all night, all night. 眠れやしない
High five, all night, all night. Can't sleep
Fly high, all night, all night. 鳴り止まない
Fly high, all night, all night. Won't stop ringing
今宵も外遊び ランタンはまるで魂
Playing outside tonight too, lanterns are just like souls
以前奇怪なジャンボリー
A strange jamboree as before
闇夜せ ハロウィン
Dark night, Halloween
ホロウ 骨抜きダンスサボター スケアクロウも 飛び跳ね回る
Holo! Boneless dance saboteur, scarecrows also jump around
ホロウ 月夜のターンテーブル クルクル愛おしい we got the party night!
Holo! Moonlit turntable, lovely excitement, we got the party night!
Anyway, enjoy the party night!
クルクル愛おしい we got the party night!
Lovely, lovely excitement, we got the party night!
パンプキンの力が乱れてる！
The pumpkins' power is going haywire!
恐れと不安が溶けていくんだ。歌の力、みんなの声の力で。
Fear and anxiety are melting away. With the power of song, and everyone's voices.
みんな乗ってるね！
Everyone's getting into it!
おかげでこっちもやる気いっぱいなのら！
Thanks to that, I'm full of motivation too!
さあ、行って。ホロウィッチ。心を苛むトリックに、
Now, go, HoloWitches. To the trick that torments the heart...
とびっきりのトリートを！
give an extraordinary treat!
みんな、応援ありがとう。思う存分、楽しんじゃうよ！
Everyone, thanks for the support. I'm going to enjoy this to my heart's content!
トリッキー！行っけー！
Tricky! Go!
わー！やられたー！
Wah! They got me!
いぇーい！
Yay!
イノセントリバイバー！
Innocent Reviver!
信じてるからね。みんなの愛が、力をくれる。
I believe in you. Everyone's love gives me strength.
はー！おりゃー！
Haa! Oryaa!
フブにゃん！ラミィちゃん、ナイス！
Fubu-nyan! Lamy-chan, nice!
それじゃあ、決めちゃうよ！はー！
Well then, let's finish this! Haa!
コン！
Kon!
ユニテリア ラミネーション！ スラッシュ トンプ コンプレッサー！
Uniteria Lamination! Slash Tomp Compressor!
は！えいやー！
Ha! Eiyaa!
ミコミコ先輩！
Miko-Miko Senpai!
サンキューんなぁ！
Thank you-nna!
テイク・イット・サファイア！
Take it, Sapphire!
へへ、みんなミコのエリートなとこ、そんなに見たいんだ。
Hehe, you all want to see my elite side that much, don't you?
しょうがないね！
I guess I have no choice then!
サイバーサクラリウム・セイバー！
Cyber Sakurarium Saber!
プリンセス・セイバー！
Princess Saber!
スラッシュヘイロー！
Slash Halo!
マリン砲！
Marine Cannon!
サンキューかなたん！
Thanks, Kanatan!
だぁ！
Dah!
みんなの思い、全部のっけて、
With everyone's feelings riding on me...
飛び込んでいくしかねーだろ！
I've just gotta dive right in!
きみたち、ちょうどいいところに来てくれるじゃん。
You guys showed up at just the right time.
みんな揃って、いいお宝ね！
All of you together... what a fine treasure!
だぁー！
Daaah!
セレスティアル・リンギング！
Celestial Ringing!
オーバースプラッシュ・ベル！
Over Splash Bell!
あいつらでラストだ！
Those guys are the last of them!
今だよ、みんな！
Now's our chance, everyone!
チェンジ！ホロウィッチ・ステッキ！
Change! HoloWitch Stick!
ウィッチ・グラム！
Witch Gram!
フルキャスト！
Full Cast!
ミオ先輩、もう大丈夫そう？
Mio-senpai, do you think you're okay now?
あ、うん。
Ah, yeah.
その、見ないようにすればなんとか。
Well... as long as I don't look at it, I'll be fine.
わかるよ。
I understand.
白上も高い所行くと下見れないからね。
Shirakami can't look down when she's in high places either.
ルナたんも虫はなるべく見ないようにしてるのら！
Luna-tan also tries her best not to look at bugs!
ありがとう、みんな。
Thanks, everyone.
みんなが助けてくれたみたいに、うちも...
Just as you all came to my aid, I...
みんなが辛いとき、苦しいときがあったら...
whenever any of you are hurting or in pain...
絶対に、絶対に力になるから！
I'll definitely, definitely be there for you!
さて、これでめでたしめでたし...
Well, now everything's well that ends well...
でもいいんだけど...
But that would be fine too...
みんな！
Everyone!
ホロウィッチの活躍、もっと見たいんじゃない？
Don't you want to see more of the holoWitches' actions?
だそうだけど...
It seems so...
やぁぁぁ〜〜！
Yaaaaay!
え、こっち？
Eh, this way?
こっち降るの？
Is it falling here?
や、あ、や... やります！
Y-A-Y... I'll do it!
よーし、やるよ、みんな！
Alright, let's do it, everyone!
おー！
Oh!
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖いものなんてない
There is nothing to be afraid of
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We are not alone anymore
大切な何かから
From something precious
壊れたあの夜に
On that night it broke
僕らは星を探して
We were looking for a star
一人で歩いていた
Walking alone
ペルセウス座に沿って
Along the constellation Perseus
君も見てただろうか
Were you also looking at it?
僕だけ元気でやっているよ
I'm doing well just fine
君は今どこにいるの
Where are you now?
「方法」という悪魔に
To the devil called "method"
魂を売らないで
Do not sell your soul
「目的」という
Called "purpose"...
大事なものを思い出して
remember what's important
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖いものなんてない
There is nothing to be afraid of
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We are not alone anymore
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖くても大丈夫
Even if you're scared, it's alright
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We are not alone anymore
大切な何かから
From something precious
壊れたあの夜に
On that night it broke
僕は君をさがして
I was looking for you
一人で歩いていた
Walking alone
あの日から僕らは
Since that day we...
一人で海を目指す
Aim for the sea alone
約束のあの場所で
In that promised place
必ずまた会おうと
To surely meet again
「世間」という悪魔に
To the devil called "society"
惑わされないで
Do not be led astray
「自分」だけが
Only "myself"...
決めた答えを思い出して
remember the answer I decided
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖いものなんてない
There is nothing to be afraid of
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We are not alone anymore
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖くても大丈夫
Even if you're scared, it's alright
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We are not alone anymore
キラメキの様な
Like a sparkle...
人生の中を
In our lives
君に出会えて
By meeting you
僕は本当によかった
I'm so glad
街を抜け海に出たら
When we leave the city and hit the sea
次はどこを目指そうか
Where shall we aim for next?
僕らはまた出かけよう
Let's set out again
愛しいこの世界を
In this lovely world
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖いものなんてない
There's nothing to be afraid of
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We're not alone anymore
空は青く澄み渡り
The sky is clear and blue
海を目指して歩く
Walking towards the sea
怖くても大丈夫
It's okay even if you're scared
僕らはもう一人じゃない
We're not alone anymore
みんな、今日はありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for today!
最高に楽しいハロウィンだったよね？みんな！
It was the best, most fun Halloween, wasn't it?
ちょっとアクシデントもあったけどさ、
There were some accidents, but,
いいお宝
A great treasure
いい思い出になったんじゃない？
Didn't it become a good memory?
ワンダー！
Wonder!
さて、そろそろお時間となってまいりましたが…
Well, it's about time to end, but...
アンコール！アンコール！
Encore! Encore!
それじゃ、アンコールにお応えして、
Then, in response to the encore,
この曲、歌っちゃうのなー！
We'll sing this song!
はじまりの魔法 -charm-！
Hajimari no Mahou -charm-!
はじまりの魔法 -charm-
The Beginning of Magic -charm-
きみに 魔法をかけるよ
I will cast a spell on you
We cast a spell on your dream!!
はじまりを告げる 衝動が響く
The impulse that signals the start echoes
気づいた時がいつだって
Whenever you realize it,
スタートラインなんだ
it's always the starting line
守るものもなかった
I had nothing to protect
キミを変えたのは
What changed you was
見つけたばかりのちっぽけな
A small, newly found
希望の輝きの原石
gemstone of shining hope
どうして 私だけ うまくいかないんだろう
Why am I the only one who can't do it right?
自分以外のすべてが 眩しく見えるけど
Everything except myself looks so dazzling
ねぇ キミに見つけてほしくて
Hey, I wanted you to find me
なりたい私になる 今こそ
I'll become the me I want to be, starting now
そうだ 叶えたい 掴みたい 夢があるから
There's a dream I want to fulfill and grasp
塞ぎこんだ日の言葉連れて
Bringing along the words from shut-in days,
歩き出すんだ
I'll start walking
信じる力が 奇跡を起こすように
So that the power of belief makes miracles happen
きみに 魔法をかけるよ
I will cast a spell on you
We cast a spell on your dream!!
叶った望みと
Fulfilled desires and
叶わない願い
unfulfilled wishes
それぞれが等しく流れてく世界で
In a world where they flow equally
何を求めて 歩き続けてるんだろう
What am I seeking as I keep walking?
いつまでもこのまま 迷い子と
Always remaining a lost child like this
キミがくれたこの空が
The sky you gave me
消えない翼をくれたね
Gave me wings that won't disappear
そうだ 照らしたい 届けたい 人がいるから
Because there's someone I want to shine for
二度ともう一人ぼっちには 戻りはしないんだ
I will never go back to being alone again
愛したい 応えたい 自分自身の日に
I want to love and respond to my own days
正解なんて これでいいと
Correct answers? "This is fine,"
見たい景色の先
at the end of the scenery I want to see
どんな場所でもいいよ
Any place is fine
どんな姿でもいい
Any form is okay
追いかけたいんだ あの煌めきを
I want to chase after that sparkle
希望を 光を 力を 連れて
Bringing hope, light, and power
抱きしめて 持っていこう
Let's embrace them and take them with us
ほら 繋げたい 広げたい 道があるから
Look, because there's a path to expand
ここから始まる 物語を
Let's walk together through
一緒に歩こう
the story that starts here
信じる力が 奇跡を起こすように
So that the power of belief makes miracles happen
君に 魔法を
I'll cast a spell...
かけるよ
...on you
ひとりじゃないから
Because you're not alone
君に 魔法をかけるよ
I'll cast a spell on you
We cast a spell on your dream!!
最高のステージだったよ、ホロウィッチ
That was a magnificent stage, HoloWitches!
本当、本当！
It really, really was!
みんな、お疲れ様！
Everyone, great work!
カノンさん、あの...
Kanon-san, um...
今日は本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much for today.
それで... あなたはどうして夢堕ちとか私たちのことを？
So... how do you know about Dream-Falling and us?
私、前に夢堕ちして...
I... Dream-Fell once before, and...
君たちに助けられたことがあるんだ
...you all were the ones who saved me.
えー！？
What!?
だから... あの時の自分と同じように...
That's why... just like I was back then...
夢堕ちして苦しんでいる誰かを見ると...
Whenever I see someone suffering from Dream-Falling...
放っておけなくて
...I just can't leave them alone.
あと、実は...
Also, the truth is...
今日このステージに出ることにしたのも...
...the reason I decided to appear on stage today...
君たちが出ると聞いたからなんだ
...was because I heard you all would be here.
もう一度会えたらって思って
I thought I might be able to see you again.
だから今日は...
So today...
えーと...
Um...
すごく嬉しかった！
...I was really happy!
これからも頑張ってね、ホロウィッチ
Keep doing your best, HoloWitches!
そ... それじゃ！
W-Well then!
また！ぜひ、また！
See you! Definitely see you again!
あの人自身が夢堕ちしてホロウィッチに助けられていたから...
It's because she herself Dream-Fell and was saved by the HoloWitches...
知っていたんだ。夢堕ちした時の辛さも...
She knew. The pain of Dream-Falling...
そんな時、誰かが手を差し伸べてくれることの嬉しさも
...and the joy of someone reaching out their hand in those times.
そっか... みこたちが少しでも誰かの力になれたら
I see... If we were able to help someone, even just a little...
その誰かがまた別の誰かの力になってくれるんだね
...then that person will go on to help someone else.
そうだね。しかもさ、それだけじゃなくて...
Right. And it's not just that...
うちらの力になってくれたりもするわけじゃん
...they end up giving us strength too, don't they?
あの人や今日応援してくれたみんなみたいに
Just like her, and everyone who cheered for us today.
それって...
That's...
それってすっごく...
That's really...
すっごくトリート！
...really a Treat!
キラキラ 宝石みたいに輝いてる
Sparkling, shining like jewels
夢の結晶 みんなの宝物
Crystals of dreams, everyone's treasure
時々 見失っちゃうこともあるけど
Sometimes we might lose sight of them, but...
溢れ出した 光が僕を呼ぶんだよ
...the overflowing light is calling out to me.
絶対 大丈夫
It'll definitely be alright
ただ まっすぐでいることも
Just staying true to yourself...
楽じゃない日もあるよね
...isn't always easy, is it?
諦めも
Giving up...
苦しみも
...and suffering...
重ねて行こう 心解き放とう
...let's pile them up and set our hearts free.
夢を 歌を
Let's take our dreams and songs...
魔法に乗せて
...and put them on a spell.
何度も立ち上がる 君と一緒に進んでいく
Standing up again and again, moving forward with you.
夢は
Our dreams...
...our dreams...
まだ終わらない 未来を取り戻そう
...will never end. Let's take back the future!
何度だって笑って
Laughing as many times as it takes,
もう一回歩き始めよう
Let's start walking once more.
ホロウィッチ おやすみ
HoloWitches, goodnight
夢の先へ
To the world beyond dreams
きらり光りだすんだよ
It starts to sparkle and shine
願ってみても
Even if I wish for it,
上手くいかない日の方が多く感じちゃったりするよね
it can feel like there are more days when things just don't go well, right?
そんな不安な悲しみも
Even those anxious, sad feelings...
抱えないで 一人じゃない
...don't carry them alone, you're not by yourself.
希望の種を 明日に蒔いたら
If we sow the seeds of hope for tomorrow,
一番に輝く 綺麗な花が咲くよ
a beautiful, brilliant flower will bloom.
夢を歌おう 魔法に乗せて
Let's sing our dreams, carried on magic,
何度も立ち上がる 君と一緒に進んでく
rising again and again, I'll move forward together with you.
夢は 夢は まだ終わらない
The dream, the dream isn't over yet,
未来を取り戻そう
let's take back our future.
何度だって笑って もう一回歩き始めよう
Smile again and again, and let's start walking once more.
ホロウィッチをさぁ 夢の先へ
holoWitch, come now, to the end of the dream.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much